我记起来了
I remember.
我看见她起来了  所以...
Saw she was up, so...
事情是怎么发生的
How'd it happen?
拜托告诉我
Please tell me.
我妈妈死了
My mother's dead.
她被咬了
She was bit.
我得眼睁睁看着她死去
I had to watch her die.
就在不久之前
Not long ago.
她相信人们  他们的灵魂
And she believed people, their -- their souls...
被困在怪物之身里
were trapped in the bodies of the monsters...
杀掉死者
that killing the dead
能让生者进入来世
lets the living move on into an afterlife.
卡尔当时正带我回你们社区
Carl was taking me back to your community,
我跟他说了我妈妈的想法
and I told him what my mother believed.
我们看到了几个行尸
And we saw a few of the dead.
他想向她致敬
He wanted to honor her.
我觉得他是想向我证明我能信任他
I think he was trying to show me that I could trust him.
事情就这样发生了
That's how it happened.
他向一个未曾谋面的女人
He died paying respects
致敬时死掉了
to a woman he never knew.
但那很危险
But it was dangerous.
那很危险  我没想到
It was dangerous, ‭and I didn't think about that.
我该想到的
I should've.
但我们失去的人们仅剩的
But all that's left of the people we lose,
属于他们的东西
what was theirs...
就是他们的思想
are their ideas.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们今天要打败他们
We're gonna beat 'em today.
是的
We are.
之后你会回神之国吗
And when we do, will you come back to the Kingdom?
我不会再逃跑了
I won't run away again.
也许吧
Maybe.
你好吗  老大
How you doin', boss?
如果今早是我们度过的最后一个早晨
If this morning is to be our last,
这会是个美好的早晨
it will be a fine morning, indeed.
最后个屁
This isn't the last of shit.
对我们的一些战友来说可能是
It could be for some of our ranks.
我接受这点
I accept that.
我屁都不接受
I'm not accepting shit.
这不是简单的接受或者悲观
It's not simple acceptance or pessimism, no.
不是那样的
Not that.
为了证明我们失去的一切是值得的
But to justify everything we've lost,
我们必须冒着失去一切的风险去战斗
we must risk losing everything.
我们屁都不会失去
We're not losing shit --
杰瑞
Jerry.
好吧
All right.
我们沿着这条路  走森林里
We'll stick to this road, keep to the trees,
我们会更快赶到
we'll get there quicker.
而且那样的话我们还可以留意这条路
Plus, we can keep an eye on the road that way.
是啊  如果他们有什么计划  我们会看到的
Yeah, if they're planning anything, we'll see it.
你觉得你可以信任格雷戈里吗
You think you can trust Gregory?
他跟我们说了什么
What he told us?
我把他锁在了房子里
I locked him up inside the house.
他知道我不会让他在这里自由走动
He knew I wouldn't ‭let him walk around free.
他知道回来后要被关起来
He knew he was coming back to that.
他只相信他自己
He doesn't believe ‭in anything except himself,
他肯定得非常相信救世军
and he'd have to believe in the Saviors a whole lot
才会把我们送进陷阱
to send us into a trap
并觉得这对他有好处
and think it would work out for him.
除非德怀特没跟他说真相
Unless Dwight didn't tell him.
那混蛋可能在设计我们
That asshole could be setting us up.
摩根
Morgan.
摩根  怎么了
Morgan, what is it?
他们不见了
They're gone.
他们有所图谋
They're doing something.
他们...
They were, uh...
他们不见了  他
They were gone -- him.
他们要进来了
They were coming in.
我问了玛姬我们能否清理墙边的行尸
I asked Maggie if we could clear the walkers from the wall.
我们引开了它们
We...drew them away
这样我们出发时就不用担心它们了
so we wouldn't have to worry about 'em when we rolled out.
是的
He did.
继续准备吧  各位
Let's keep gettin' ready, everyone.
第一支小队20分钟后出发
First team's going in 20.
你刚说"我们出发时"
You said when we roll out.
你和你的人不去
You and your people aren't coming.
你可以留在这里
You can be here.
但你不是我们的一员
But you're not us.
说清楚了就好
As long as we got that straight.
也许你不该和我们一起去
Maybe you shouldn't come with us.
我必须去
I have to.
你做得已经够多了
You've done plenty.
我必须去
I have to.
-摩根  -瑞克
- Morgan -- - ‭Rick.
我必须去  我必须去...
I have to. I have t-to...
关键不在我
It's not me.
而在于其他人  我得保护他们
It's everybody else, and I'm gonna keep 'em alive.
我得保护亨利不受...
I'm gonna keep Henry from...f--
我们...
We...
我们越变越糟了  我和你
We are worse than we were... me and you.
真的
We are.
你之前在酒吧里对那些人讲的那番话
Giving your word to those men back at the bar.
那是不可避免的  没错  但是...
I mean, it's what it took, yeah, but...
那事没那么简单
But that was something else.
你不该做那种事
That was something wrong for you.
而我们越界是因为
And we crossed into it because -- because...
我们都失去了一切  一切美好的事物
we've both lost everything, everything good.
那...
What --
那我们现在竭尽所有保护大家
What does it matter if we spend whatever's left
还有什么意义呢
on keeping people alive?
因为我们并没有失去一切
Because we haven't lost everything.
-没有完全失去  -已经失去了
- Not yet. ‭- We have.
而且我们无法回头
And we can't go back.
所以让我们快点了结吧
So let's just finish this.
《行尸走肉》
真惨啊  是不是  小德
Sucks, don't it, D?
之前就算你脸上
I mean, even with that disgusting,
有那块恶心的疤痕
knotted cheese on the side of your face,
大家还是尊重你的
you once had these people's respect.
但现在呢
But now?
现在你一无所有
Well, now you don't have a damn thing.
带他上车
Load him up.
这不是我的子弹制造者嘛
There's my bullet maker.
本人随队行动
Attaché in tow
订单如承诺般迅速完成
and order fulfilled PDQ, as promised.
每一发子弹都由在下亲自进行质量把关
Every munition personally quality-controlled by yours truly.
不睡觉  拼命干
Sleep be damned and efforts be tripled,
任务完成
the deed is done.
请您试用
Take yourself a tester.
瑞克
瑞吉娜和你说过计划了  是吧
Regina laid out the plan for you, right?
所以我才要求随队行动
That's why I requested the ride-along.
鉴于地形和时机
Depending on the terrain and timing,
以及紧张局势
the pump and priming,
我认为应尝试一击制敌
I believe we should attempt a one-fell-swooper.
列队射击降低混乱率
A firing line that would minimize chaos opportunity
十分钟内就能结束战斗
and alpha-to-omega this thing in less than 10.
你确定你想看到这一幕吗
Are you sure that's something you want to see?
准确地说是"需要"看到
More of a "need to" Thing.
瞧瞧你
Look at you.
把东西都装好  出发
Let's load up, roll out!
兰斯  杜克  去伯耶兰路
Lance, Duke -- Boylan Road.
如果出事了  地图上有写我会去哪
Map will show you where I'll be if there's trouble.
不用了  我们牢牢记在脑海里了  老大
No, we got this one locked down, Jefe.
太好了
Damn straight you do.
蠢货
Idiots.
你不如也一起来吧  小加
Why don't you tag along, Gabey?
这趟旅程不错的
It's a nice drive.
我想忏悔一些事
I got some shit that I want to confess.
保佑我吧  神父  我有罪
Bless me, father, for I have sin
也许吧
probably.
随时就要开始了
Any second now.
我派到路上去设置行尸路障的那些人
Now, those men I sent out down there on their road setting up their road block with the dead,
对自己马上要丧命这点一无所知
not knowing they're joining their cold asses any second.
因为瑞克和他那群混蛋
Cos Rick and his band of pricks
马上就要袭击他们了
will gonna hit them on.
我并不享受让自己人去送死
You know, I don't enjoy sacrificing my own people.
你清楚这点吧
You know that, right?
那些人支持过西蒙
I mean, those guys back there, they came up with Simon.
总有人得为团队做牺牲
Some of us had to take one for the team,
那就让他们牺牲吧
it may as well be them.
我还是不明白
I still don't understand.
小瑞克得到了一些消息
Ricky was slipped some intel,
以为他能抢在我之前行动
make him think he can get the jump on me.
事实上  那消息的来源不太靠谱
The thing is, it came from a less-than-reliable source,
所以如果我是他  我会先探探路
so if I were him, I'd be scouting ahead.
干掉那个路障小队
Taking out that little road-block crew
会让瑞克以为得到了我位置的确切消息
is gonna make Rick think he's got the real story, where I'll really be.
他们会来找我
They'll come to get me.
但那才是陷阱
But, see, that is the trap.
那才是伏击他们的办法
And that is how we will get them.
他们会找到一张地图
they are gonna find the map
写着我要去的时间和地点
with the time and place I will be
他们会坚信不疑
and they gonna believe it
因为他们不会留活口
because they will have killed all of those poor bastards.
我投降
I give up!
我投降  我认输
I give up! I'm done!
我投降
I'm done! Aah!
哥们  太变态了
Dude! That was messed up.
我是说  天啊
I mean, Jesus.
你死不了  对吧
You don't die, right?
哥们
Man...
你应该找机会试试
You oughta try it sometime.
听着
Listen...
你不会以为看过那么多人死
You don't think you can kill your way out of this
你能靠杀人摆脱吧  对吧
seeing everybody else go, do you?
让我来告诉你
'Cause let me tell you...
摆脱不了的
not gonna happen.
摩根
Morgan?
你没事吧
Are you with us?
很好  在我们的采石场找到了线索
Good people, found something on our quarry.
什么线索
What is it?
一个单子和另一张地图
A list and another map.
似乎和我们的不一样
And what appear to be other facts.
救世军在老磨坊路列队呢
They're lining up Saviors on the Old Mill Road.
尼根一定会去那
That's where Negan will be.
我们得在他们知道这里的事之前找到尼根
We have to get to Negan before they figure out what happened here.
玛姬
Maggie.
我在
I'm here.
是时候了
It's time.
确实是陷阱
It was a trap.
所以我们要改变计划
So we're changing the plan.
就这吗
So that's it?
你要忏悔的就是
Your confession is that you're...
你要杀光他们所有人吗
gonna kill every last one of them?
你以前忏悔的时候  看起来
When you spoke before, you seemed almost
好像真心不希望这种事发生
as if you didn't want it to happen.
这与希望无关  小加
It ain't about want, Gabey.
从来都是无关的
It never was.
不
No!
出发
Come on, let's go!
别去  他什么都看不清
Hang back! He can't see crap.
尤金  我必须警告他们
Eugene, I have to warn them.
-你不能这么做  -闭上你的臭嘴
- You can't do this. - Shut up. Shut your damn mouth,
不然我会用自制弹药
or so help me, I will use a homemade munition
在此时此地打爆你的颅骨
to crack your cranium right here, right now!
懂了吗
Do you understand?
Do you?!
懂了
Yes.
看看你
Look at you.
真正需要的时候  你的信仰又在哪
Where does your faith go when you truly need it?
在我看来  现在才是最该坚持信仰的时候
Seems to me it's the only time worth holding on to.
抱歉  尤金
Sorry, Eugene.
小加得归我处置
I'm gonna have to call dibs on Gabey boy myself.
你说过你不想无谓牺牲
You said you didn't want to die a fruitless death.
人不能实现所有愿望
Well, you can't always get what you want.
带他上车
Load him into the car.
你想保护这些人
You want to keep these people safe,
为了这个目的你觉得自己必须杀人
and you think you need to kill other people to do that.
这对你来说并不安全
That's not exactly safe for you,
最终也会给你要保护的人带来危险
which ultimately may not be safe for the people you're trying to keep safe.
这是个难题
It's a conundrum.
又或者不是
Or it's not.
但不杀人也可以阻止他们
But you can stop people without killing them.
我是说  以前你差点阻止过我
I mean, you almost stopped me.
我有个简单的提议
I have a simple proposal.
可以试试
Something to try.
这一端对付死人  这一端对付活人
This end for the dead, and this end for the living.
情况会变好的
And things will get better.
耶稣
Jesus.
我开始喜欢这家伙了
I'm starting to like that guy.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
该死
Holy damn.
你见过这么大的尸群吗
You ever seen one that big?
没有
No.
一切都在变
Things are changing.
我们走
Let's go.
-还有多远  -越来越近了
- How much further? - We grow closer.
那边  过桥
Yonder, over the ridge.
救世军
Saviors!
该死  瑞克  瞧瞧
Well, damn, Rick, look at that.
又中计了  又大大地中计了
Pegged again. Pegged so very hard.
我用更大的埋伏
I ambushed your ambush
埋伏了你的埋伏
with an even bigger ambush.
你何不正大光明地出来  面对我们
How about you step out and face us?!
我无处不在  瑞克
Oh, I am everywhere, Rick.
到处都有扩音器
Some more bullhorns,
都有对讲机
more walkies.
选个逃跑的方向吧
Pick a direction to run.
看看你能跑多远
See how you do.
让我们都找点乐子
Make it fun for all of us.
你猜我还做了什么
Guess what else I did.
我还带了几个你的老朋友来
I brought you some of your old friends.
你还记得你的老朋友尤金吗
You remember your old buddy Eugene?
是他造就了今天的一切
Well, he is the person that made today possible.
这位小德怀特也一样
Same goes for Dwighty boy here.
如果你想知道的话  他不是故意出卖你的
In case you were wondering, he didn't ream you on purpose.
不  他只是...一个没种的废物
No, he is just a -- a gutless nothin' that sucks at life,
现在他要站在这里  眼睁睁看着你们死
and now he gets to stand up here and watch you all die,
并背负这一切
and he's gonna live with that.
加百利
Gabriel, well...
他也得死
...he's got to go, too.
今天我们要清理门户  瑞克
We are cleaning house today, Rick.
然后...就轮到你了
And then...there's you.
根本没必要战斗
It never had to be a fight.
你只用接受事实
You just had to accept how things are.
那么
So...
开始吧
here we go.
恭喜你  瑞克
Congratulations, Rick.
Now!
尤金
Eugene!
他要跑了
He's running!
格雷戈里已经出来了吗
Is Gregory already out here?
我们把他留在屋里了
We left him inside the house.
把他交给他们吧
Let them have him. Shh!
继续走  去集合点
Keep going. To the rendezvous point.
其他人应该已经到了
The others should already be there.
-等等  -怎么了
- Hold up! - What's going on?
我去试试拖住他们
I'm gonna try and slow them down.
去吧  去吧
Go, go.
就你一个人吗
What, just you?
他们能听到她的声音
Look, they can hear her.
-在新泽西都能听到  -这我说不准
- They can hear her in New Jersey. - I don't know about Jersey,
但我不会让你一个人去
but I'm not letting you do this by yourself.
你觉得我可能给你枪吗
You think I'm gonna give you a gun?
给不给我都会留下来
I'm gonna stay one way or another.
有想跟我一起的吗
Any of you gents with me?
因为我跟她一起
'Cause I'm with her.
就算她不把我们当自己人
Even if she's not with us.
是他干的  抓住他
He did this! Get him!
摩根
Morgan.
你不用这么做
You don't have to.
把这里清理了吧
Let's clean this up now, shall we?
再等一下
Give it another second.
别开枪
Don't shoot.
拜托
Please.
我们输了
We're done.
结束了
It's over.
告诉你一件事
Just so you know,
点兵点将
eenie meenie miney moe,
都是胡扯
that was bullshit.
我做了选择
I made a choice.
我只是不想在一个孩子面前杀死他的父亲
I just didn't want to kill a kid's dad in front of him.
现在看来  杀你才是我最好的选择
Turns out that would've been the best thing I could've done.
如果当初我杀了你  那孩子还能活着
Had I done it, ‭that kid might still be alive.
你被打败了
You're beat.
你的人都倒下了
Your people are down.
我会脱身的
I'll get out of it.
一向如此
I always do.
只剩你和我了  瑞克
It's just you and me, Rick.
而你  你内心支离破碎
And you -- you are torn open.
我更高大  更坏
I am bigger, I am badder,
还有根球棒
and I got a bat.
我们可以有未来
We can have a future.
我知道我有
I know I will.
给我十秒钟
Just give me -- give me 10 seconds
我能跟你解释
so I can -- I can tell you how.
不
No.
为了卡尔  给我十秒钟
Just give me 10 seconds for Carl.
十
10...
九
9...
卡尔说没必要...
Carl said it doesn't have to be --
没必要非得战斗
it doesn't have to be a fight anymore.
他错了  八
He was wrong. 8...
不  不  他说得对
No, no. He was right.
看你做了什么
Look what you did.
卡尔什么都不知道
Carl didn't know a damn thing...
救他
Save him.
不  玛姬  玛姬
No! ‭Maggie! Maggie!
不  不行
No, he can't!
不
No!
不  他杀了格伦
No, he killed Glenn!
我们必须救他
We have to.
我们必须了结这一切
We have to end it!
瑞克
Rick!
我们必须纠正错误
We have to make it right!
纠正不了的  但这能结束一切
We can't make it right, but this makes it over.
-结束了  -不
- It's over. - ‭No!
没结束
It's not over!
他死了才算结束
It's not over until he's dead!
It's not over till he's dead!
不
No!
No.
不
所发生过的  我们所做过的
What happened, what we did...
我们所失去的
what we lost...
未来一定不只如此
there's gotta be something after.
举起手的都把手放下
The ones who have 'em up, put your hands down.
我们现在都要回家了
We're all gonna go home now.
尼根还活着
Negan's alive.
但他那套结束了
But his way of doing things is over.
不能接受这一点的人
And anyone who can't live with that
将会付出代价  我保证
will pay the price, I promise you that.
今天在场的
And any person here
任何崇尚和平公正的人
who would live in peace and fairness...
愿意求同存异的人
who would find common ground...
这个世界属于你们
this world is yours, by right.
我们是活人
We are life.
那些是死人
That's death!
它们要来杀我们
And it's coming for us.
除非我们团结一致
Unless we stand together!
所以回家吧
So go home.
然后开始工作
Then the work begins.
迎接新世界
The new world begins.
这一切
All this...
这一切都过去了
All this is just what was.
未来一定不只如此
There's gotta be somethin' after.
他们的枪是怎么回事
What happened to their guns?
是你干的吗
Was that you?
没错
It was.
我瞒着同事们
I introduced a sabotaging aspect
在制造过程中加入了破坏的一环
to the manufacturing process unbeknownst to my colleagues,
灵感来源于加百利故意的笨拙
inspired by Gabriel's purposeful ineptitude.
还有我吐在你身上前  你告诉我的一些事
And a few things you imparted to me before I vomited on you.
所以  我用一点小手段制造出了大故障
Ergo, I created a modicum of phooey for a full kablooey.
这是为了你吐在我身上
That's for the puke.
很公平
Fair play.
给亨利的
It's for Henry.
你能否告诉他  我不会有事的
Will you tell him I'm gonna be okay?
真的吗
Are you?
我会努力的
I'm gonna try.
我知道我必须没事
I know I need to be.
愿我的仁慈
My mercy...
胜过我的怒火
prevails...over my wrath.
打扰一下  玛姬
Excuse me. Maggie?
他们要回救世堂
The...guys are going back to the Sanctuary.
打算把那里改造成别的样子
Gonna...try and make something else out of it.
我不知道
I don't know.
实际上
The thing is...
我一直都不属于那
I was never meant to be there.
我看了那本书
I-I've been reading that book, uh...
《通向未来的钥匙》
"A Key to a Future."
我可以造东西
You know, I-I can build things,
我可以把书中某部分变成真的
I can make some of that stuff real,
为这个地方  为这些人
for -- for this place, for these people.
我想这样过我的人生
It -- It's what I want to do with my life.
说真的  你给了我那样的生活  所以
And, no joke, you, uh -- you gave me that life, so...
好的
Okay.
很高兴你能来
Glad you're here.
很高兴来这里  我想是的
Glad to be here. I think.
我们知道
Well, we know.
那是你们的人吗
That you guys?
对  又拉了些玻璃
Yeah, more glass.
又叫了些人帮忙一块安回去
And more people to help put it back together.
出去
Get out.
我知道自己为什么来这
I know why I'm here.
我知道自己对丹妮斯做了什么
I know what I did to Denise.
对你
To you.
对其他人做了什么
To other people.
原因并不重要
And it doesn't matter why.
我知道我必须面对
I knew I'd have to face it...
付出代价  我应该这样
to pay, and I should.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我得看到尼根被打败  这就够了
I got to see Negan taken down, and that's enough.
而我呢
Me?
我就是个混球
I'm a piece of shit.
回不去了
There's no going back to how things were.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的很对不起
Look, I'm so sorry.
拜托
Please.
求你了
闭嘴
Shut up.
你走吧  别停下
You go, and you keep going.
别再回来
Don't you ever come back here again.
如果再让我在附近看到你的脸
If I ever see ‭your face around here again,
我就杀了你
I'll kill you.
去外面  弥补自己的过错
You go out there, and you make it right.
找到她
Find her.
我是瑞克的朋友
I'm a friend of Rick's.
从亚历山大来的
From Alexandria.
他说你可以去社区
He says you can come back to the community.
如果你想的话
If you wanna.
为什么
Why?
瑞克想建造些东西
Rick is trying to build something.
需要尽可能多的人手
He needs ‭all the hands he can get.
他想展示给大家一切是可以改变的
He wants to show people that things can change.
你不想自己一个人过的
You don't want to be alone.
人
People.
人是最重要的
Everything is about people.
人是生命中最重要的东西
Everything in this life that's worth a damn.
你叫什么
What's your name?
摩根·琼斯
Morgan Jones.
你可以叫我安妮
You can call me Anne.
我去收拾东西
Let me get my things.
-我们就可以走了  -你走吧
- We can go. - ‭Or you can go.
我会留下
I'm gonna stay.
我想自己待着
I want to be alone. I, um...
我需要独处
I need to be.
你刚才不是说...
I thought you said --
他们是  但我不能
They are, but I can't.
我做不到
I can't.
蜜月
我想说你是对的
I just wanted to say you were right.
救下卫星站的救世军
About saving the Saviors from the satellite outpost.
让他们待在这
Having them here.
我不后悔自己的所作所为
I don't regret what I did.
但你是对的
But you were right.
瑞克决定不杀掉全部救世军也是对的
And Rick was right about not killing all the Saviors.
他是对的
He was right.
当时是
He was.
但尼根的事不是
Not about Negan.
你打算怎么做  玛姬
So what does that mean, Maggie?
我们有很多事要做
We have a lot to do.
我们要把这地方建起来
We have to build this place up,
让它比以前更好
make it work better than before,
让这里繁荣兴旺
make it thrive ‭for the people who live here.
我们要有力量
We need our strength,
要有更强的防御力
the ability ‭to defend ourselves better.
我们必须有
We have to have that.
会有的
We will.
但是瑞克和米琼恩
But Rick and Michonne...
瑞克做了错事
Rick was wrong to do what he did.
米琼恩也是
Michonne, too.
所以我们要潜心发展  等待时机
So we're gonna bide our time, wait for our moment...
然后我们会让他明白的
and then we're gonna show him.
是的
Yeah.
我们会的
We will.
我们知道你醒了
We know you're awake.
我没说过我没醒
I never said I wasn't.
很好
Good.
因为我们要告诉你一些事
Because we need ‭to tell you some things.
你现在不用睁眼
And you don't ‭have to open your eyes now.
但你很快会睁开的
But you're gonna open them soon.
因为我们会逼你见证一切
Because we're gonna make you watch what happens.
这不是因为你杀过谁
And this isn't about who you killed.
不  我们也杀过人
No, we've -- we killed people.
这是因为你对我们做过的事
No, this is about what you did to us,
你对很多人做过的事
what you did to so many people.
你强迫别人侍奉你
How you made people live for you,
你强迫别人服从你
how you put people under your boot.
我救了人
I saved people!
米琼恩
Michonne.
他得知道
He needs to know.
这不是商量
This isn't a discussion.
我们可以拆开他的线来提醒他
We can open up his stitches for a little while just to remind him.
卡尔设想了更好的未来
Carl pictured something better.
我们所有人一起合作
All of us working together
创造比我们更伟大的东西
for something bigger than all of us.
你也有自己的工作
And you'll have a job, too.
是的
Yeah.
你也有自己的角色
You get to be a part of it.
你会成为一个反例
You'll be an example of what this will be.
我们不会杀你
We're not gonna kill you.
我们不会伤你
We're not gonna hurt you.
你会坐穿牢底
You're gonna rot in a cell.
你的下半生  一天接一天
For the rest of your life, day after day.
你会成为我们创造文明的证据
You're gonna be evidence that we're makin' a civilization,
我们过去拥有的文明
something like what we had,
我们将会重建的文明
something we're gonna get back.
而你得看着它发生
And you get to watch it happen.
你会看到你对
And you get to see how wrong you were
人性和生活的错估
about what people can be, about what life can be.
你活着  会让人们明白一切改变了
You, alive, ‭is gonna help show people that things have changed,
允许你活着  换来了另一条更好的出路
that keepin' you breathing earns another way, a better way.
这就是你要扮演的角色
That's the part you'll play.
所以经历了这么多
So after all this...
或许你终于有点用了
maybe you're good for something.
谢谢
Thank you.
我明白了
I understand.
我现在知道了
I know now.
您给了我很多
You've given me so much...
您给过我很多
...after you've given me so much.
我能看到了
I can see.
亲爱的卡尔
Dear Carl.
我记起来了
I remember.
我忘了自己是谁
I forgot who I was.
你让我记起来了
You made me remember.
我记得那天和你散步的感受
I remember that feeling, walking with you that day.
就像我人生中第一次知道了自己是谁
Like I finally knew who I was for the first time in my life.
虽然我们在一起走
Thing is, we were walking side-by-side,
但其实是你在带我去某处
but you were bringin' me somewhere.
带我来了这里
Bringin' me here.
带我们所有人来了新世界  卡尔
Bringin' all of us to the new world, Carl.
你向我展示了新世界
You showed me the new world.
你使之成真
You made it real.
我看到了
I see it.
我记起了
I remember.
爸爸
Dad.